Shiva Gaire



geeksambhu@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/geeksambhu



+977 9847340073



https://dev.shivagaire.com.np

Summary

Software engineer with almost 5 years of experience in software development. Highly experienced in all aspects of the software development lifecycle, software architecture design, project management practices from concept through to development and delivery. Designed, built and delivered software solutions with a focus on scalability, performance and incorporating cloud native technologies.

Experience

lp S

Senior Software Engineer

Logpoint

May 2022 - Present (4 months +)

- Led migration of first-generation on-premise alert and incident engine to the cloud that significantly reduced computation cost on on-prem LogPoint installation
- Conceptualized and built SMS notification with SMPP support to current notification engine that helped to onboard prospective telecommunication customer
- Mentored the team of 3 engineers in the current team.

Technologies: Python, Flask, Docker, Terraform

Software Engineer

Logpoint

May 2020 - May 2022 (2 years 1 month)

Responsibilities:

- Built core web server architecture for SIEM application that triggers incident and Alerts from different log sources,
- Integrated MITRE ATT&CK Knowledge base
- Built unique licensing models for LogPoint SIEM product and other sub-products (SOAR & Logpoint Cloud).

Tech Stack: Python, Flask, MongoDB,

lp

Associate Software Engineer

Logpoint

Jan 2018 - May 2020 (2 years 5 months)

SIEM Sizing Calculator

- Designed and built an application to calculate SIEM infrastructure needs that increased marketing lead generation by 60%

LogPoint Documentation Portal

- Designed and built application/pipeline to build documentation in Restructured Text format available in Version Control System to desired formats.(HTML/PDF).

LogPoint License Portal

- Enhanced security of existing License model for LogPoint and added licensing model for subproducts Director & UEBA.

Tech Stack: Flask, Django, Django Rest Framework, React/Redux, express.js MongoDB

Professional Intern

Logpoint

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017 (4 months)

- Responsible for maintaining LogPoint customer portal
- Responsible for developing and Maintaining LogPoint's Developer Portal for supporting artefacts for LogPoint metaprogramming Architecture

Education



Kathford International College

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering

2013 - 2017

Volunteered at Campus Free and open-source software community(Kathford FOSS community) which aim to promote use,

adapt and contribute to open-source software along with building the technological ability of students.

Licenses & Certifications



GitOps Fundamental - Codefresh

61ca99c3fd35b6273a187856



Blockchain Specialization - Coursera

N5F5B5NG7LHE

Skills

Python • Flask • Django • Kubernetes • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • MongoDB • PostgreSQL

• Express.js • Software Architecture • Docker Products